portero.com 2008-06-18

# Online Luxury Internet Auctions by Portero.com | Designer & Luxury Watches, Jewelry, Collectibles & Art | Buy It Now or Bid Auction Style at Portero

| 

_Home_

| Privacy, Authenticity, Safety & Security 

Your privacy is important to us. Accordingly, we have designed this privacy policy in order to communicate what information Portero collects, why we collect this information, and how we use the information we collect. 

**Collection and Use of Information:** Generally, you can browse our Web Site without providing any personally identifiable information. Personally identifiable information is any information that may be used to identify an individual, including, but not limited to your: name; home, billing or other physical address; email address; phone number or other contact information; and a credit card number and expiration date. In the event you register with Portero, you are giving us your consent to the collection, use, and disclosure of this personally identifiable information in accordance with the terms of this privacy policy. 

**Communications:** Should you provide Portero with personally identifiable information, this information may be used to communicate with you in order to, among other things, alert you as to information regarding Portero or its products and services that we believe may be of interest to you. If you are the successful bidder on a Portero auction or otherwise submit a purchase request with Portero, we will use your personally identifiable information to confirm your transaction, attempt to prevent and detect fraud or abuse, respond to your requests or inquiries, provide you with other administrative information regarding your order, and provide you with any other information we deem helpful to you. We want to communicate with you only if you want to hear from us. If at any time you do not wish to receive communications from Portero, you may elect to opt-out of receiving further email by clicking on the unsubscribe link in any email promotion sent to you. 

**Compliance with Law and Fraud Protection:** We may provide access to personally identifiable information when legally required to do so, to cooperate with police investigations or other legal proceedings, to protect against misuse or unauthorized use of our Web Site, to limit our legal liability, and to protect our rights or the rights, property, or safety of visitors to this Web Site or of the public. We may collect and possibly share personally identifiable information and any other information available to us in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, or as otherwise required by law. We may also exchange information, including personally identifiable information, with other companies and organizations for credit fraud protection and risk reduction.

**Internal Use:** We may from time to time review your personally identifiable information for errors, omissions, and accuracy. We may also use your personally identifiable information internally to improve our marketing and promotional efforts, Web Site content, and product offerings. 

**Service Providers:** Portero will not sell, trade, or rent your personally identifiable information to third parties, unless you have granted us permission to do so. We may, however, share your personally identifiable information with authorized third party service providers. Examples of authorized third parties that we may share your personal information with include, but may not be limited to: web hosting companies, shipping companies, third party consulting or marketing firms, and e-mail service providers. Additionally, if you use a credit card or other financing alternative to place an order with Portero, to confirm and process your order we will share your personally identifiable information with such financing company. These third parties only receive personally identifiable information if such information is needed to perform their function(s), and they are not authorized to use any personally identifiable information for any other purpose(s). 

**Sharing of Information:** In addition to sharing information with service providers (as set forth above), we may share personal data with consignors, brand owners, retailers, and manufacturers with whom we are engaged if we believe their products may be of interest to you. 

**Business Transfer:** We may transfer or share a copy of personal information about you in the event that Portero, or one of its affiliates or subsidiaries, goes through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of a portion of its assets. You will be notified via email or prominent notice on our web site prior to a change of ownership or control of your personal information if your personal information will be used contrary to this privacy policy. Portero specifically reserves the right to transfer or share a copy of personally identifiable information collected from its websites to the buyer of that portion of its business relating to that information. 

**Data Collection Devices, such as Cookies:** Cookies are small pieces of information sent to your Web browser and stored on your hard drive to help us provide you with a more effective and interesting shopping experience. Since our site may not function correctly with cookies disabled, we strongly recommend that you leave them enabled. However, if you would like to be notified when a cookie may be written, set your browser to stop accepting new cookies. To disallow the use of cookies altogether, please see the "Help" option in your browser's toolbar. 

**Security:** Portero is committed to protecting your privacy in accordance with the terms of this privacy policy and we will use appropriate security measures to protect the personal information you provide to us, including the use of a Secure Socket Layer (SSL). However, no internet data transmission can be guaranteed to be secure from access by unintended parties, and, by registering with us and providing personal information, you agree that you will not hold us responsible for any breach of security unless such breach is due to our gross negligence or deliberate violation of this privacy policy. Please note that if you have logged into Portero.com from a shared computer, it is important that you sign off your account before leaving that computer. 

_**Portero's Authenticity Guarantee**_

We at Portero believe that buying luxury goods online should be straightforward, exciting, and without risk. Portero's mission is to be the leading trusted online source for authenticated, pre-owned, luxury Jewelry, Watches, Accessories, Art, and Fine Housewares. Portero guarantees that each item on our web site is 100% authentic. 

We deliver on our promise of authenticity by drawing on the experience of our in-house category specialists, by working with outside product experts, and by partnering with selected luxury brands and other leading luxury companies, such as Tourneau, the world's largest luxury watch retailer. 

_**Authentication Process by Category:**_  
**WATCHES:**  
Tourneau certifies the authenticity of our pre-owned watches. The watch case and movement are thoroughly inspected to confirm the authenticity and operability of the watch. Portero offers a one-year warranty on service repair through Tourneau and other reputable repair service providers. Click here for more details

**JEWELRY:**  
In addition to our in-house specialists, Portero employs the services of a GIA certified jeweler who inspects and confirms the authenticity of all jewelry. This process includes close inspection of workmanship, jewelers' stamps, and quality of material and stones. 

Through our partnerships with Kwiat and Robert Lee Morris, these brands certify that the Kwiat and Robert Lee Morris items sold on our site are authentic. Each Kwiat and Robert Lee Morris auction listing will display a seal signifying that the item is certified authentic by the respective brand. 

**ART:**  
Portero employs the services of a Christie's and Sotheby's trained art curator who personally selects each piece and verifies its origin. 

**FINE HOUSEWARES:**  
Portero's in-house Fine Housewares specialists closely inspect workmanship, designer and brand stamps, and verify the pieces with known pieces by the designer/brand. Through our partnership with Lalique, Lalique certifies that the Lalique products sold on our web site are authentic. Each Lalique auction listing will display a seal signifying that the item is certified authentic. 

**ACCESSORIES:**  
In addition to our in-house specialists, Portero employs the services of accessories experts who have experience authenticating and selling pre-owned luxury handbags and leather accessories, and who closely inspect workmanship, material quality, and stitching, as well as hardware and designer/brand authenticity stamps on every bag. 

**Should you ever wish to discuss the authenticity of an item you have purchased from us, please contact Portero Customer Care by one of the following three easy methods:**  
1) 'Live Chat': instant messaging by clicking on the 'Live Chat' link on any page   
2) Email: [customercare@portero.com](mailto:customercare@portero.com)  
3) Phone: toll free (in the US) at 1.877.307.3767

**Customer Care Business Hours:**  
Monday-Friday: 9am-5pm US Eastern (all forms of Customer Care support)  
Sunday-Thursday: 4pm-Midnight US Eastern (Live Chat and email support)

**LEGAL DISCLAIMER** : We make every effort to ensure the accuracy of our prices and information. However, mistakes and typographical errors may nevertheless occur. We reserve the right to correct those errors, and we apologize in advance for any inconvenience. In the event a transaction that was predicated on misinformation is completed, Portero reserves the right to cancel the transaction with no further liability on its part. Brand names are the trademarks of their respective owners and are not affiliated with Portero. In the event an item sold by Portero is determined to be inauthentic, Portero will refund the purchase price as well as any shipping and insurance charges incurred by the buyer. This refund shall constitute the buyer's full and complete remedy. 

At Portero.com, your personal online security is a priority. We use the latest SSL encryption technology to store and safely transmit your personal and credit card information through our systems. We use a highly secure check out system provided by Truition, Inc. to process all orders. Additionally, for your safety and protection we confirm that your billing address exactly matches the address on file with your credit card company. 

Your privacy is important to us, and we have strict policies regarding the use of your personal information. Click here to read our privacy policy.
